<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uvm_directories on Home</title>
    <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uvm_directories on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.121.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 11:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UVM Report Object</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_23_11_00_17_uvm_repor_object/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_23_11_00_17_uvm_repor_object/</guid>
      <description>Source &amp;ndash; UVM Framework Directory
The uvm_report_object provides an interface to the UVM reporting facility. UVM reporting plays a crucial role in tracking the progress of the testbench, identifying issues, and debugging. It provies a rich set fo message display commands and methods to track and report erros, warnings and information.
Figure 1: UVM Reporting Classes
The methods in uvm_report_object are delegated to the uvm_report_handler, which manages reporting configurations such as actions, verbosity, and other settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVM Base Class Library</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_22_09_38_07_uvm_base_class_library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 09:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_22_09_38_07_uvm_base_class_library/</guid>
      <description>UVM Framework Directory
The base class library in UVM serve as the building blocks for any testbench and verification environment. These classes provide reusable, modular components that help create a structured and scalable framework, ensuring efficiency and consistency across various test environments.
Figure 1: UVM Base Class
The UVM class library offers a wide range of built-in features for verification, including printing, copying, test phases, and more. Each component in the testbench architecture can be derived from the corresponding UVM class, which enhances readability and reduces development time, making the verification process more efficient and streamlined.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVM Testbench Overview</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_22_08_54_25_uvm_testbench_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_22_08_54_25_uvm_testbench_overview/</guid>
      <description>UVM Framework Directory
The UVM testbench follows a layered architecture, where each component is dedicated to a specific task and interacts with the rest of the testbench through well-defined interfaces. This design promotes modularity and reusability, making it easier to manage and extend the testbench. Figure 1 illustrates a typical UVM testbench architecture.
Figure 1: UVM Testbench Architecture
UVM Testbench The UVM Testbench is the top-level module in the hierarchy, where both the UVM Test and the Design Under Test (DUT) are instantiated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVM Workflow in Vivado</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_04_14_44_52_uvm_workflow_in_vivado/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_09_04_14_44_52_uvm_workflow_in_vivado/</guid>
      <description>UVM &amp;ndash; UVM Vivado Script &amp;ndash; UVM Python Script
The UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) workflow is centered around creating a testbench that integrates key UVM components such as drivers, monitors, and scoreboards, alongside the essential UVM library setup. Numerous commercial tools are available for simulating and verifying digital designs, including ModelSim, Cadence Xcelium, Synopsys VCS, Aldec Riviera-PRO, and Vivado Simulator. Another excellent option for experimenting with small-to-medium-sized verification projects is EDA Playground.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVM Framework Directory</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_08_28_12_39_50_uvm_framework_directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_08_28_12_39_50_uvm_framework_directory/</guid>
      <description>UVM stands for Universal Verification Method developed by UVM Working Group that provides a standardized methodology for verifying digital integrated circuits. UVM is built on top of SystemVerilog and provides a useful framework for creating reusable and scalable testbenchs. The framework provides a set of building blocks or pre-built design kits that help to create a complex system in a more organized and efficient way instead of building everything from scratch.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>