<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>cstr on Home</title>
    <link>https://24x7fpga.com/tags/cstr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cstr on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.121.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://24x7fpga.com/tags/cstr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic Random Number Without Using Randc</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2025_01_10_cyclic_random_number_without_using_randc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2025_01_10_cyclic_random_number_without_using_randc/</guid>
      <description>Source &amp;ndash; Constraint Challenges &amp;ndash; SV Verification Directory
Problem Statement Generate a sequence of non-repeating random numbers stored in an array. The solution should ensure that each number appears only once and should cover all possible values in the specified range. Do not use the randc function in SystemVerilog.
Randc Randc is a built-in command in SystemVerilog designed to generate random variables in a cyclic manner. Unlike standard randomization methods, randc ensures that all possible values within the specified range are generated exactly once before any value repeats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divide by X</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_12_14_divide_by_x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 21:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_12_14_divide_by_x/</guid>
      <description>Source &amp;ndash; Constraint Challenges &amp;ndash; SV Verification Directory
Problem Statement Create a constraint to generate an N-bit random number that is divisible by a given natural number X. The value of X is parameterized, allowing it to be easily changed for different test scenarios.
Problem Breakdown The key idea is to ensure that the random number generated satisfies the condition below:
\begin{equation} \label{eq.1} NUM \quad \% \quad X == 0 \end{equation}</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate Diagonal Zeros/Ones</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_11_29_21_53_39_generate_diagonal_zeros_ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 21:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_11_29_21_53_39_generate_diagonal_zeros_ones/</guid>
      <description>Source &amp;ndash; Constraint Challenges &amp;ndash; SV Verification Directory
Problem Statement Write a constraint to generate an N×N matrix where diagonal elements are set to zeros (or ones), while the rest of the matrix can be filled with either random values or a predefined value.
Problem Breakdown To make the solution more manageable, we can decompose the constraint into smaller, focused sub-constraints:
Generate an N×N Matrix: Define a rand array to hold the matrix values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraint Challenges</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_11_12_18_40_22_constraint_challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_11_12_18_40_22_constraint_challenges/</guid>
      <description>GitHub &amp;ndash; SV Verification Directory
Constraints in SystemVerilog play a vital role in verification by enabling robust and efficient generation of test scenarios that thoroughly exercise the design under test (DUT). When designing a verification environment, especially for complex digital designs, simply testing with fixed values isn’t sufficient.
Learning constraints in SystemVerilog is crucial for verification because they enable controlled randomization, helping engineers generate targeted, meaningful test cases while covering a wide range of scenarios.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>