<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>toc on Home</title>
    <link>https://24x7fpga.com/tags/toc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in toc on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.121.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:40:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://24x7fpga.com/tags/toc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Constraint Challenges</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_11_12_18_40_22_constraint_challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_11_12_18_40_22_constraint_challenges/</guid>
      <description>GitHub &amp;ndash; SV Verification Directory
Constraints in SystemVerilog play a vital role in verification by enabling robust and efficient generation of test scenarios that thoroughly exercise the design under test (DUT). When designing a verification environment, especially for complex digital designs, simply testing with fixed values isn’t sufficient.
Learning constraints in SystemVerilog is crucial for verification because they enable controlled randomization, helping engineers generate targeted, meaningful test cases while covering a wide range of scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVM Framework Directory</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_08_28_12_39_50_uvm_framework_directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/uvm_directory/2024_08_28_12_39_50_uvm_framework_directory/</guid>
      <description>UVM stands for Universal Verification Method developed by UVM Working Group that provides a standardized methodology for verifying digital integrated circuits. UVM is built on top of SystemVerilog and provides a useful framework for creating reusable and scalable testbenchs. The framework provides a set of building blocks or pre-built design kits that help to create a complex system in a more organized and efficient way instead of building everything from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SV Verification Directory</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_06_27_16_53_00_sv_verification_directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/sv_directory/2024_06_27_16_53_00_sv_verification_directory/</guid>
      <description>In the rapidly evolving world of digital design, verification is paramount to ensuring that designs function correctly and efficiently. SystemVerilog, an extension of the Verilog hardware description language, has become a critical tool for verification engineers. This blog post aims to introduce SystemVerilog verification, highlighting its significance, features, and basic concepts to help you get started on your verification journey.
Automated Workflow in Vivado SV Verification Workflow in Vivado Layered Testbench SV Testbench Overview SV Scheduling Semantics Scheduling Semantics Data Types Logic Type Fixed-Size Arrays Packed and Unpacked Array Dynamic Arrays Queues Associative Arrays Array Methods Enumeration Structures Streaming Operator Type Converstion Static Cast Dynamic Cast Flow Control For and Foreach Loops While and Do While Loops Repeat and Forever Break and Continue Tasks and Functions Tasks Functions Process Fork Join Fork Join Any Fork Join None Wait Fork Disable Fork OOP in SV Object-Oriented Programming Class Handle Object Method This Keyword Static Class Properties and Methods Shallow Copy and Deep Copy Four Pillars of OOP Inheritance Super Keyword Virtual Keyword Polymorphism Encapsulation Interprocess Communication Events Mailbox Semaphore Interface Interface Modport Clocking Block Randomization $urandom and $urandom_range rand and randc Constraint Randomization Constraint: Inside Operator Constraint: Array Randomization Constraint: Bidirectional and Conditional Constraint: Implication and Equivalence Constraint: Solve-Before Constraint: Weighted Distribution Constraint: In-line and External SV Mastery Challenges Constraint Challenges Verification Examples Half Adder Full Adder Adder Subtractor </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RTL Design Directory</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_05_00_21_53_rtl_design_directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_05_00_21_53_rtl_design_directory/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my comprehensive collection of RTL(Register Transfer Level) designs. It is an evolving collection highlighting my projects, skills, and achievements in digital circuit design and verification. I specialize in developing efficient, high-performance hardware architectures using industry-standard languages like SystemVerilog and Verilog. Explore my blog for insightful articles on the latest trends and best practices in RTL design, and visit the tutorials section for step-by-step guides to mastering this critical aspect of hardware engineering.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>