<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Rtl_directories on Home</title>
    <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rtl_directories on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.121.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 19:54:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shift Register</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_19_54_50_shift_register/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 19:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_19_54_50_shift_register/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Shift Register: An Overview A shift register is a set of sequential registers placed in series to transfer and store data. The figure below shows a 4-bit serial shift register.
The waveform below shows the data being shifted from flip-flop 1 to 4 on the rising edge of the clock.
Applications Shift registers are typically used to collect and transfer data for various applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Register</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_19_23_36_register/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 19:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_19_23_36_register/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Register: An Overview A register in digital design is fast storage sequenctial circuit that can hold data temporarily. A widely used register is D Flip-FLop. A D Flip-Flop is an edge-triggered circuit that combines a pair of latches to store on bit.
Advantages of Registers Registers provide fast access to data compared to main memory. Ideal for temporary storage during data processing. Desgin: D Flip-Flop A D Flip-Flop is a edge-trigger register, either postive edge-triggered, negative edge-triggered or dual edge-triggered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adder-Subtractor</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_16_50_01_adder_subtractor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 16:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_16_50_01_adder_subtractor/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Adder-Subtractor: An Overview An adder-subtractor is a combinational digital circuit that can perform the operation of an adder and subtractor based on the control signal. It is an essential component in arithmetic logic units (ALUs) in microprocessors and digital signal processors.
Applications of Adder-Subtractor CPUs, microcontrollers, and digital signal processors implement adder subtractors for arithmetic operations. Computer graphics make use of adder-subtractors blocks for calculating coordinates and pixel values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparator</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_15_54_47_comparator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_07_06_15_54_47_comparator/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Comparator: An Overview A comparator is a fundamental building block in digital design that compares two binary numbers. Comparators can be categorized based on their use and functionality.
Equality Comparator: it compares the two binary numbers to up a true bit or high when all the binary bits are identical and false or low when the bits are not identical. Magnitude Comparator: has three functionality, to determine the relationship between the two binary numbers that are being compared.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoder</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_23_21_30_22_decoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_23_21_30_22_decoder/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Decoder: An Overview The functionality of a decoder is the opposite of an Encoder. A decoder is a combinational circuit that converts a binary coder to a set of output signals with only one bit of the being high at any given time. It consists of N input lines and 2^N output lines.
Design: 2-to-4 Decoder A 2-to-4 decoder consists of two input lines and four output lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encoder</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_23_20_40_25_encoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 20:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_23_20_40_25_encoder/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Encoder: An Overview An encoder is a digital combinational circuit that converts 2^n inputs to n outputs. It converts a set of binary inputs to binary-coded output, where only one input line is active at a given time.
Design: 4-to-2 Encoder A 4-to-2 encoder, where n = 2 i.e., it consists of 2^n = 2^2 = 4 input lines named as in[3], in[2], in[1], in[0] and two output lines named as out[1] and out[0].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Multiplexer</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_14_22_07_44_de_multiplexer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 22:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_14_22_07_44_de_multiplexer/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
De-Multiplexer (DEMUX): An Overview A DEMUX or data distributor is a one-to-many combinational circuit that receives inputs from a single input line and transmits the same information over one of &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; possible output lines. DEMUX transmits the same data that is received on the input to different destinations. A de-multiplexer is a 1-to-N device, where N/n is the number of outputs and with &amp;rsquo;m&amp;rsquo; select line, therefore, 2^m = n.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiplexer</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_13_12_22_45_multiplexer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 12:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_13_12_22_45_multiplexer/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Multiplexer (MUX): An Overview A multiplexer is a digital circuit that selects one input out of many inputs, hence, it is also called a data selector. It consists of 2^n inputs with n selector lines, which are used to select which input to send to the output.
Need For Multiplexers The need for MUXs arises wherever there is a need to transmit multiple data over a shared communication channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Adder</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_08_11_32_42_full_adder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 11:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_08_11_32_42_full_adder/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Full Adder A full adder is a basic building block of a digital circuit. Full adder requires three inputs a, b, and c(carry-in) to result in two outputs s(sum) and co(carry-out).
Full adder truth table:
A B C SUM (S) Carry (Co) 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 1 1 0 0 1 0 1 0 0 1 1 0 1 1 0 0 1 0 1 0 1 0 1 1 1 0 0 1 1 1 1 1 1 Boolean equation for sum and carry is :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half Adder</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_05_22_56_41_half_adder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 22:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_05_22_56_41_half_adder/</guid>
      <description>Design &amp;ndash; Testbench &amp;ndash; RTL Design Directory
Half Adder Half adder is a combinational arithmetic circuit. Its functionality is to add two 1-bit binary digits to produce a sum bit and carry as the output.
Half adder truth table:
A B Sum (S) Carry (Co) 0 0 0 0 0 1 1 0 1 0 1 0 1 1 0 1 Boolean equation for sum and carry can be written as :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RTL Design Directory</title>
      <link>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_05_00_21_53_rtl_design_directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://24x7fpga.com/rtl_directory/2024_06_05_00_21_53_rtl_design_directory/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my comprehensive collection of RTL(Register Transfer Level) designs. It is an evolving collection highlighting my projects, skills, and achievements in digital circuit design and verification. I specialize in developing efficient, high-performance hardware architectures using industry-standard languages like SystemVerilog and Verilog. Explore my blog for insightful articles on the latest trends and best practices in RTL design, and visit the tutorials section for step-by-step guides to mastering this critical aspect of hardware engineering.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>